Title: Regulations on Facilities and Clinicians Providing Abortions | The Henry J. Kaiser Family Foundation						
"Timeframe: as of June 1, 2016"						
"For footnotes, please see: http://kff.org/womens-health-policy/state-indicator/regulations-on-facilities-and-clinicians-providing-abortions/?currentTimeframe=0."						
Location	Clinic must meet structural standards comparable to ambulatory surgical centers	Corridor width and/or procedure room size specified	Maximum distance between clinics and hospital specified	Transfer agreement with hospital in event of complications required	Hospital admitting privileges for clinicians required	Hospital admitting privileges or alternative agreements for clinicians required
United States	22 states	16 states	10 states	8 states	5 states	8 states
Alabama	Yes	Corridor width	No	No	Hospital privileges; policy not in effect	Hospital privileges or alternative agreement
Alaska	No	No	No	No	No	No
Arizona	Yes	No	30 miles	No	No	Hospital privileges or alternative agreement
Arkansas	Yes	Procedure room size	30 miles	No	No	Hospital privileges or alternative agreement; policy not in effect
California	No	No	No	No	No	No
Colorado	No	No	No	No	No	No
Connecticut	Yes	No	No	No	No	No
Delaware	No	No	No	No	No	No
District of Columbia	No	No	No	No	No	No
Florida	Yes	No	No	No	No	Hospital privileges or alternative agreement
Georgia	No	No	No	No	No	No
Hawaii	No	No	No	No	No	No
Idaho	No	No	No	No	No	No
Illinois	No	No	No	No	No	No
Indiana	No	Corridor width and procedure room size	Adjacent County	No	No	Hospital privileges or alternative agreement
Iowa	No	No	No	No	No	No
Kansas	Yes; policy not in effect	No	30 miles; Policy not in effect	No	Hospital privileges; policy not in effect	No
Kentucky	Yes	No	No	Yes	No	No
Louisiana	Yes	Procedure room size	30 miles; Policy not in effect	No	Hospital privileges; policy not in effect	Hospital privileges or alternative agreement
Maine	No	No	No	No	No	No
Maryland	Yes	No	No	No	No	No
Massachusetts	No	No	No	No	No	No
Michigan	Yes	Corridor width and procedure room size	30 minutes	Yes	No	No
Minnesota	No	No	No	No	No	No
Mississippi	Yes	Corridor width and procedure room size	30 minutes	No	Hospital privileges; policy not in effect	Hospital privileges or alternative agreement
Missouri	Yes	Corridor width	15 minutes	No	Hospital privileges	No
Montana	No	No	No	No	No	No
Nebraska	Yes	Procedure room size	No	Yes	No	No
Nevada	No	No	No	No	No	No
New Hampshire	No	No	No	No	No	No
New Jersey	No	No	No	No	No	No
New Mexico	No	No	No	No	No	No
New York	No	No	No	No	No	No
North Carolina	Yes	No	No	No	No	No
North Dakota	No	No	30 miles	No	Hospital privileges	No
Ohio	Yes	No	30 miles	Yes	No	No
Oklahoma	Yes	Procedure room size	30 miles; Policy not in effect	No	Hospital privileges; policy not in effect	Hospital privileges or alternative agreement
Oregon	No	No	No	No	No	No
Pennsylvania	Yes	Corridor width and procedure room size	No	Yes	No	No
Rhode Island	Yes	No	No	No	No	No
South Carolina	Yes	Corridor width	No	No	No	Hospital privileges or alternative agreement
South Dakota	Yes	Corridor width	No	No	No	No
Tennessee	Yes	Corridor width and procedure room size	Adjacent County	Yes	Hospital privileges	No
Texas	Yes; policy not in effect	Corridor width and procedure room size; policy not in effect	30 miles; Policy not in effect	Policy not in effect	Hospital privileges	No
Utah	Yes	Procedure room size	15 minutes	No	Hospital privileges	No
Vermont	No	No	No	No	No	No
Virginia	Yes	Corridor width and procedure room size	No	Yes	No	No
Washington	No	No	No	No	No	No
West Virginia	No	No	No	No	No	No
Wisconsin	No	No	No	Yes	Hospital privileges; policy not in effect	No
Wyoming	No	No	No	No	No	No
						
Sources						
"Guttmacher Institute, State Policies in Brief, [Targeted Regulation of Abortion Providers](https://www.guttmacher.org/state-policy/explore/targeted-regulation-abortion-providers), as of June 1, 2016."						
						
Definitions						
"*Clinic must meet structural standards comparable to ambulatory surgical centers*: Requirements for meeting ambulatory surgical center standards can include specifications such as the following: maintaining standard operating rooms, adequate lighting and ventilation for abortion procedures, surgical examination tables and other fixed equipment, emergency exits to accommodate a stretcher or gurney, areas for sterilizing instruments, dressing rooms, procedure rooms, and more."						
						
*Hospital admitting privileges*: Hospital privileges laws require doctors who perform abortion to have admitting privileges at a hospital within a certain distance of the clinic.						
						
"*Hospital admitting privileges or alternative agreements for clinicians required*: State requires providers to have either admitting privileges or an alternative agreement. Alternative agreements include an agreement with another physician who has admitting privileges, or other arrangements."						
						
*No*: Specified policy not in effect in state indicated.						
